avert.org 2019-06-12

# Avert.org privacy policy | AVERT

Thank you for using Avert.org. Here, we explain what personal information we may hold about you, and how we might use that information. By using our website you are agreeing to the terms of this privacy policy, and to the [terms and conditions](https://www.avert.org/node/381) of use of this website. Words defined in those terms and conditions of use have the same meaning when we use them in this policy. If you have any questions about this privacy policy, please email [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#731a1d151c3312051601075d1c0114).  

Please note that where our website contains links to other websites, we are not responsible for the privacy policies of other organisations and websites and this policy applies solely to any personal information collected on Avert.org.

## **What information do we collect?**

Personal information is any information that can be used to identify a living individual such as a name, date of birth, email address, postal address, and telephone number.

Any personal information that you provide us with is stored securely. We may collect this personal information when you contact us, give feedback through our comments boxes, submit a personal story, make a donation, register for our services (for example, to receive our newsletter), or otherwise give us personal information.

When making a donation, your financial information such as credit and debit card details, is stored by [Stripe](https://stripe.com/gb) and [GoCardless](https://gocardless.com/) (for UK direct debit) only and Avert does not have access to this information.

## **How do we use this information?**

We use your personal information to provide you with the information or services you ask for. We may also use your information for administrative purposes, including letting you know about changes to our services and understanding more about how our website is used. In addition, we may handle any non-sensitive personal data for our legitimate purposes. We will not sell your details to any third parties or use your data in any other way than those listed above.

Avert regards the lawful and correct handling of personal information as important to the success of our work and to maintaining the confidence of those with whom we deal. This applies to any user of our services, irrespective of where they live.

We will ensure that anyone working for us uses personal information lawfully and correctly. To this end, we will ensure we fully comply with the EU General Data Protection Regulations.

## **How we use cookies**

A cookie is a small text file passed to your computer, mobile phone or other device, through your web browser, so that the website remembers who you are when you return.

We use cookies on our websites to collect anonymised data on user activity and interactions.

We use website analytics tools, such as Google Analytics and Hotjar, to track how the website is used. These tools use cookies to gather statistics about how people use the website. For example, to see how many people look at a particular web page and which country they are from.

This information allows us to improve the website and to keep it relevant to our users’ needs. We do not store any personal information for this purpose but simply use it to see how you use the website.

If you do not wish to have cookies stored on your computer, you can easily change your web browser’s settings to refuse cookies. Information about deleting or controlling cookies is available at [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

Please note that by deleting our cookies or disabling future cookies you may not be able to access certain areas or features of our website. The [International Chambers of Commerce](http://www.iccwbo.uk/pages/privacy) provides a guide to the law in this area and information about different types of cookies.

### Google Analytics

Google Analytics is a web analytics service provided by Google that enables us to measure how people use our website using cookies. We use this information to improve our website experience for website visitors and to measure the effectiveness of our online advertising.

If you’d prefer to opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites, visit <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

### Hotjar [](https://www.hotjar.com/?utm_source=badge)

Hotjar is a website analytics tool we use to see how our supporters are moving around our website and get feedback through surveys, so that we can improve their experience and help ensure they can find what they are looking for.

## Signing-up for our newsletters

When you sign-up to receive newsletters from us, you are asked to provide your name and email address. This personal data is shared with a third-party company based outside the EU called [MailChimp](https://mailchimp.com/), whose system we use to send email newsletters to our subscribers. Any data you provide is stored on secure servers by MailChimp.

MailChimp is compliant with the [EU-US Privacy Shield Framework](https://www.privacyshield.gov/), which means they comply with data protection requirements. For the purposes of GDPR, Avert is deemed the ‘Data Controller’ and MailChimp the ‘Data Processor’. You can find out more about [how MailChimp manages data](http://www.mailchimp.com/legal/privacy).

## Accessing your data

We want to make sure that your personal information is accurate and up-to-date. You may ask us to correct or remove information you think is inaccurate. You also have the right to request a copy of the information that we hold about you at any time. To do so, please email: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#9cf5f2faf3dcfdeaf9eee8b2f3eefba3efe9fef6f9ffe8a1cfe9fef6f9ffe8b9aeacfdfffff9efefb9aeaceef9ede9f9efe8) or write to the Chief Executive, Avert, First Floor South, 6-7 Lovers Walk, Brighton BN1 6AH.

If you wish to make a complaint about how we have handled your personal data, please email: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#97fef9f1f8d7f6e1f2e5e3b9f8e5f0a8e4e2f5fdf2f4e3aad4f8fae7fbf6fef9e3b2a5a7f6f5f8e2e3b2a5a7fff6f9f3fbfef9f0b2a5a7f8f1b2a5a7e7f2e5e4f8f9f6fbb2a5a7f3f6e3f6) or write to the Chief Executive, Avert, First Floor South, 6-7 Lovers Walk, Brighton BN1 6AH, and we will investigate the matter.

If you are not satisfied with our response or believe we are not processing your data in accordance with the law, you can contact the [UK’s Information Commissioner’s Office](http://www.ico.org.uk/).

**Updated April 2018**
